YULIA KUCHINA

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER

PORTFOLIO
0437 591 190
kuchina@gmail.com
LinkedIn
Sydney
Australian citizen

SKILLS

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Libraries React, React-Native, Next.js, Sentry, Jest, Cypress, Styled Components,

SCSS, Material-UI and more

APIs GraphQL, REST

Extra Azure, Firebase, Git, Github actions, CI/CD, Agile, Web3, React Hooks,

Redux, Zustand, Flow, PostCSS, Sass, Storybook, Webpack,

Special Abilities Complex Data visualisations using D3 or React + canvas

3D in a browser (tree.js, babylon.js, deck.gl)

Maps (leaflet, Mapbox, Maplibre)

Web3

I am a React developer with more than 7 years of commercial React experience and more than 10 years of Front End development. I am a fast learner with a good math background and a love for clean code and functional programming.

I strongly believe in engineering excellence and continuous learning and improvement. I constantly research and experiment with new technologies and innovative ideas. I am always happy to take other people on that journey and share my findings and inspiration.

I have extensive experience building web applications for both desktop and mobile devices. I worked on projects for companies like **Big W, Rural Fire Service NSW, Revenue NSW, ABC and Centennial Coal.**

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Big W | 10/2023 - Current

Senior front-end engineer, contract

- Implementation of new features for the checkout and payments section of the Big W web store. React, Typescript, Next.js, Sentry, Storybook, Cypress, Jest.
- Deployments to production, updating existing codebase to modern clean code standards, writing

more tests to ensure correct app work, attending design sessions to help create seamless user experience, reviewing pull requests

mentoring younger developers

Kablamo | 05/2022 - 09/2023

Senior front-end engineer, 12-month contract, extended

- Developing an Aviation Safety dashboard for NSW RFS.
 React, Typescript, Next.js, Mapbox, Maplibre, Storybook, Jest.
- Implementation of scenario prediction feature for the Firestory (bushfire prediction app). React, Typescript, Mapbox, Storybook, Jest
- Developing forge.polemos.io web3 platform for gamers to exchange knowledge and game NFTs. React, Typescript, Wagmi, @web3modal, Gitlab, styled-components, Storybook, Jest

Revenue NSW | 09/2021 - 05/2022

Senior front-end engineer, 6-month contract, extended

• Developing Land Tax Payments application. Creating coding tests for interviews. React, Typescript, rxjs, Redux, Gitlab, styled-components, Storybook, Jest

Kablamo | 03/2021 - 09/2021

Senior front-end engineer, contract

- <u>ABC triple j Unearthed project.</u> Created a functionality for a new react app to upload and manage musical tracks and allow users to leave reviews.
- Worked in a team to develop a <u>firetrail.io</u> web app for bushfire analysis and predictions.
 Implemented multiple Mapbox and deck.gl layers to toggle critical infrastructure objects, prediction isochrones, firetrucks updated locations, etc.

React, Typescript, Next.js, Flow, Mapbox, deck.gl, styled-components, Storybook, Jest

Adrennial | 11/2020 - 03/2021

Front-end engineer

- Designed and developed complex interactive tree visualisations for the company ticketing system, based on USL model.
- Designed and developed highly interactive UI for transcribing tool: subtitles editor with interactive diagram (length, time, distribution, highlighted current).
- Worked across multiple projects to implement new features.
 React, Typescript, Next.js, Material-UI, FireStore, REST API, Jest, React-testing library, D3, Storybook

Centennial Coal | 06/2019 - 11/2020

Senior front-end engineer

- Worked as only Front-End dev across seven projects for the last eight months. Designed, developed and maintained multiple projects.
- Shift Performance Tool: a React-Native app to let a user choose a list of the miners to see the current machine status.
- Real-time Performance Monitor application: a mobile/desktop dashboard.
- Workorders Board App: adjusting and expanding a trello-like web board to suit specific project requirements.
- Development of report application A PWA that allows quick creation of forms and reports, using react-json schema form as a base.
 - React, React-Native, Redux, Typescript, GraphQL, Jest, Material-UI, Storybook

Anditi | 09/2017 – 05/2019

Front-end engineer

- 3D portal for measurements in 3D models (point cloud and meshes). Implemented an octree to speed up a search of intersections in models, UI measurement tools including point of interest, distance, height tool, transect tool, annotations, volute, etc. Short demo video (from 1:00)
- Designed and developed a solar panel placement web app. Users can draw a roof plane on a map, place panels automatically or custom, rotate panels to a better fit, load solar potential image derived with the reflection of the site location, calculate energy output estimation and generate a pdf report.
- Developed Anditi Art, and maintained Anditi website.
 React, Redux, Typescript, Three.js, D3, Leaflet, Styled Components, Jest

Increaseo | 03/2017 - 06/2017

Front-end engineer, contract

Development of WordPress websites. Creating complex, highly interactional SVG diagrams. Managing hosting (backups, databases). WordPress, PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap, CPanel

Devspire Software | 2015–2017

Front-end engineer, self-employed

Designed and developed an income tax calculator. Residents and non-residents can calculate tax by taxable year, included or not superannuation and student loan, different payment options, etc Designed and developed https://openwage.com.au/ to visualise open Australian Taxation Office data about average individual income by occupation, state, region and years.

Customer support at http://abncheck.com.au/ (part-time)

Javascript, jQuery, Grails, Bootstrap

Design of new features and UI, content management, and customer support at https://readmanga.live

Systematica Business Software | 11/2007 – 04/2008 Java Developer

Creating complex SQL-based reports on the government social payments database. Bug fixing in Java code. SQL, Java

Orenburg State University | 2002–2005 *Web developer*

Implemented a new university website design, performed maintenance and development of CMS. Technical support for end-users.

Designed and developed Scientific Research Magazine Vestnik and Phone Directory Application, including CMS for both.

PHP, SQL, XSLT, XML, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Computer Science and Mathematics Orenburg State Pedagogical University 1998–2003